Voiceover: When observing
the natural world,
many of us notice a somewhat
beautiful dichotomy.
No two things are ever exactly alike,
but they all seem to follow
some underlying form.
Plato believed that the true forms
of the universe were hidden from us.
Through observation of the natural world,
we could merely acquire
approximate knowledge of them.
They were hidden blueprints.
The pure forms were only
accessible through abstract
reasoning of philosophy and mathematics.
For example, the circle he describes
as that which has the distance
from its circumference to
its center everywhere equal.
Yet we will never find
a material manifestation
of a perfect circle or a
perfectly straight line.
Though interestingly, Plato speculated
that after an uncountable number of years,
the universe will reach an ideal state,
returning to its perfect form.
This Platonic focus on abstract pure forms
remained popular for centuries.
It wasn't until the 16th century
when people tried to embrace the messy
variation in the real world
and apply mathematics to
tease out underlying patterns.
Bernoulli refined the idea of expectation.
He was focused on a method
of accurately estimating
the unknown probability
of some event based on
the number of times the event
occurs in independent trials.
He uses a simple example.
Suppose that without your knowledge,
3,000 light pebbles and 2,000 dark pebbles
are hidden in an urn,
and that to determine
the ratio of white versus
black by experiment,
you draw one pebble after another,
with replacement, and note how many times
a white pebble is drawn versus black.
He went on to prove
that the expected value
of white versus black observations
will converge on the actual ratio
as the number of trials increases,
known as the weak law of large numbers.