And it wasn't until
1785, and there were many
that came before Coulomb,
but in 1785 Coulomb formally published
what is known as Coulomb's law.
And the purpose of Coulomb's law,
Coulomb's law,
is to predict what is
going to be the force of
the electrostatic force
of attraction or repulsion
between two forces.
And so in Coulomb's law, what it states is
is if I have two charges,
so let me, let's say this
charge right over here,
and I'm gonna make it in white,
because it could be positive or negative,
but I'll just make it q
one, it has some charge.
And then I have in Coulombs.
and then another charge
q two right over here.
Another charge, q two.
And then I have the distance
between them being r.
So the distance between these two charges
is going to be r.
Coulomb's law states that the force,
that the magnitude of the force,
so it could be a repulsive force
or it could be an attractive force,
which would tell us the
direction of the force
between the two charges,
but the magnitude of the force,
which I'll just write it as F,
the magnitude of the electrostatic force,
I'll write this sub e here,
this subscript e for electrostatic.
Coulomb stated, well this is going to be,
and he tested this, he didn't
just kind of guess this.
People actually were assuming
that it had something
to do with the products of the magnitude
of the charges and that as the particles
got further and further away
the electrostatic force dissipated.
But he was able to actually measure this
and feel really good
about stating this law.
Saying that the magnitude
of the electrostatic force
is proportional,
to the product of the
magnitudes of the charges.
So I could write this
as q one times q two,
and I could take the
absolute value of each,
which is the same thing as just
taking the absolute value of the product.
Here's why I'm taking the
absolute value of the product,
well, if they're different charges,
this will be a negative number,
but we just want the overall
magnitude of the force.
So we could take, it's proportional to
the absolute value of the
product of the charges
and it's inversely proportional to
not just the distance between them,
not just to r, but to the
square of the distance.
The square of the distance between them.