adenosine triphosphate, and
even when we look at its
molecular structure it seems
quite involved, but if we break
it down into its constituent
parts it becomes a little bit
more understandable and we'll
begin to appreciate why,
how it is a store of energy
in biological systems.
The first part is to break
down this molecule between
the part that is adenosine
and the part that
is the triphosphates, or
the three phosphoryl groups.
The adenosine is this
part of the molecule,
let me do it in that same color.
This part right over here is adenosine,
and it's an adenine connected to a ribose
right over there, that's
the adenosine part.
And then you have three phosphoryl groups,
and when they break off they
can turn into a phosphate.
The triphosphate part
you have, triphosphate,
you have one phosphoryl
group, two phosphoryl groups,
two phosphoryl groups and
three phosphoryl groups.
One way that you can conceptualize
this molecule which will
make it a little bit easier
to understand how it's a store
of energy in biological systems
is to represent this whole
adenosine group, let's just
represent that as an A.
Actually let's make that an Ad.
Then let's just show it bonded to
the three phosphoryl groups.
I'll make those with a P
and a circle around it.
You can do it like that,
or sometimes you'll see it
actually depicted, instead
of just drawing these
straight horizontal lines
you'll see it depicted
with essentially higher energy bonds.
You'll see something like that to show
that these bonds have a lot of energy.
But I'll just do it this way
for the sake of this video.
These are high energy bonds.
What does that mean, what does that
mean that these are high energy bonds?
It means that the electrons
in this bond are in a
high energy state, and if
somehow this bond could be
broken these electrons are
going to go into a more
comfortable state, into
a lower energy state.
As they go from a higher
energy state into a lower, more
comfortable energy state they
are going to release energy.